Register of the Trotsky collection, 1917-1995
Hoover Institution Archives
- V. I. LENIN FILE, 1917-1924 (Box 1-9)
  - Correspondence
    - Others to Leon Trotsky
      - Shliapnikov, Aleksandr, 1918 November 25 (Folder 79)
      - Sklianskii, Efraim
        - 1919
          - May 23 (Folder 80)
          - May 24 (Folder 81)
          - August 12 (Folder 82)
        - 1920
          - February 11 (Folder 83)
          - September 13 (Folder 84)
      - Smirnov, Ivan, 1920 January 26 (Folder 85)
      - Sokol'nikov, Grigorii, 1920 May 5 (Folder 86-87)
      - Stasova, Elena, 1919
        - July 26 (Folder 88)
        - July 28 (Folder 89)
        - August 17 (Folder 90)
        - September 18 (Folder 91)
      - Sverdlov, Iakov, 1918
        - August 31 (Folder 92)
        - September 8 (Folder 93)
        - September 10 (Folder 94)
        - December 13 (Folder 95)
      - Tukhachevskii, Mikhail, 1920 January 19 (Folder 96)
      - Unidentified, 1918 June 7 (Folder 97)
      - Vatsetis, Ioakim, 1919 June 22 (Folder 98)
      - Zinov'ev, Grigorii, 1919 April 15 (Folder 99)
    - V. I. Lenin to others
      - Antonov-Ovseenko, Vladimir, 1919
        - April 22 (Box 6, Folder 1)
        - April 25 (Folder 2)
        - May 29 (Folder 3)
      - Astrakhan' (R.S.F.S.R.) Revoliutsionnyi Voennyi Sovet, 1919 May 18 (Folder 4)
      - Averin, Vasilii, 1919 June 13 (Folder 5)
      - Beloborodov, Aleksandr, 1919 June 10 (Folder 6)
      - Bubnov, Andrei, 1919 June 5 (Folder 7)
      - Danishevskii, Karl, 1920 August 11 (Folder 8)
      - Dzerzhinskii, Feliks, (ca.), 1920 August 28-31 (Folder 9)
      - Efremov, M. I., 1919 June 6 (Folder 10)
      - Evetskii, Apollon, 1919 August 9 (Folder 11)
      - Frumkin, Moisei, 1922 December 12 (Folder 12)
      - Frunze, Mikhail
        - 1919
          - May 12 (Folder 13)
          - May 22 (Folder 14)
          - July 1 (Folder 15)
          - July 25 (Folder 16)
          - October 18 (Folder 17)
          - November 2 (Folder 18)
        - 1920
          - October 16 (Folder 19)
          - October 28 (Folder 20)
      - Gittis, Vladimir, 1919 October 21 (Folder 21)
      - Gol'dberg, B. I., 1919
        - October 19 (Folder 22)
        - November 1 (Folder 23)
      - Gusev, Sergei
        - 1919
          - April 26 (Folder 24)
          - May 29 (Folder 25)
          - June 3 (Folder 26)
          - June 4 (Folder 27)
          - June 6 (Folder 28)
          - June 11 (Folder 29-30)
          - June 16 (Folder 31)
        - 1920 September 13 (Folder 32)
      - Ioffe, Adol'f, 1918 June 10-15 (Folder 33)
      - Kamenev, Lev, 1919 May 26 (Folder 34)
      - Kolegaev, Andrei, 1919 May 21 (Folder 35)
      - Kuz'min, N. N., 1920 March 5 (Folder 36)
      - Lashevich, Mikhail
        - 1919
          - June 9 (Folder 37)
          - June 11 (Folder 38)
          - June 18 (Folder 39)
          - June 20 (Folder 40)
          - June 27 (Folder 41)
          - July 17 (Folder 42)
          - August 28 (Folder 43)
        - 1920 May 27 (Folder 44)
      - Mekhonoshin, Konstantin, 1919
        - April 24 (Folder 45)
        - April 26 (Folder 46)
      - Mel'nichanskii, Grigorii, 1919 June 9 (Folder 47)
      - Mitskevich-Kapsukas, Vikentii, 1920 August 20 (Folder 48)
      - Molotov, Viacheslav, 1922 April 9 (Folder 49-50)
      - Narimanov, Nariman, 1921 September 26 (Folder 51)
      - Ordzhonikidze, Grigorii
        - 1920
          - April 3 (Folder 52)
          - April 20 (Folder 53)
          - August 20 (Folder 54)
          - September 9 (Folder 55)
        - 1921
          - March 29 (Folder 56)
          - March 30 (Folder 57)
          - April 5 (Folder 58)
          - April 9 (Folder 59)
      - Peterson, Karl, 1919 October 25 (Folder 60)
      - Petrogradskii Komitet Oborony, 1919 May 27 (Folder 61)
      - Podvoiskii, Nikolai, 1919 May 31 (Folder 62)
      - Rakovskii, Khristian, 1919
        - April 20 (Folder 63)
        - April 24 (Folder 64)
        - May 8 (Folder 65)
        - May 22 (Folder 66)
        - May 24 (Folder 67)
        - May 26 (Folder 68)
        - May 28 (Folder 69)
        - June 12 (Folder 70)
        - July 11 (Folder 71)
      - Raskol'nikov, F., 1919 October 30 (Folder 72)
      - Rozengol'ts, Arkadii, 1919 August 1 (Folder 73)
      - Russian S.F.S.R. Raboche-Krestianskaia Krasnaia Armiia. Armiia, 3-ia, 1920 January 12 (Folder 74)
      - Russian S.F.S.R. Raboche-Krestianskaia Krasnaia Armiia. Armiia, 5-ia, 1919 October 21 (Folder 75)
      - Russian S.F.S.R. Raboche-Krestianskaia Krasnaia Armiia. Armiia, 10-ia, 1919 May 18 (Folder 76)
      - Russian S.F.S.R. Raboche-Krestianskaia Krasnaia Armiia. Armiia, 11-ia, 1921 March 10 (Folder 77)
      - Russian S.F.S.R. Raboche-Krestianskaia Krasnaia Armiia. Eshelonyi Poezd, 54, 1918 July 27 (Folder 78)
      - Russian S.F.S.R. Raboche-Krestianskaia Krasnaia Armiia. Zapasnaia Armiia, 1920 February 8 (Folder 79)
      - Russian S.F.S.R. Revoliutsionnyi Voennyi Sovet Respubliki (Iuzhfront)
        - 1919
          - June 14 (Folder 80)
          - June 21 (Folder 81)
        - 1920 November 12 (Folder 82)
      - Russian S.F.S.R. Revoliutsionnyi Voennyi Sovet Respubliki (Zapfront), 1919 April 24 (Folder 83)
      - Russian S.F.S.R. Tsentral'nyi Otdel Voennykh Zagotovok, 1919 November 8 (Folder 84)
      - Shumskii, Aleksandr, 1920 March 23 (Folder 85)
      - Siberia. Tsentral'nyi Ispolnitel'nyi Komitet, (ca.), 1918 April 5-8 (Folder 86-87)
      - Sklianskii, Efraim
        - 1917 November 28 (Box 7, Folder 1)
        - 1918
          - August 9 (Folder 2)
          - August 16 (Folder 3)
        - 1919
          - (ca.), March 1-15 (Folder 4)
          - April (day unknown) (Folder 5)
          - April 2 (Folder 6)
          - April 10 (Folder 7)
          - April 24 (Folder 8)
          - April 26 (Folder 9)
          - May 15 (Folder 10)
          - June 8 (Folder 11)
          - June 9 (Folder 12)
          - (ca.), June 10-11 (Folder 13)
          - July 4 (Folder 14)
          - July 5 (Folder 15)
          - July 8 (Folder 16)
          - (ca.), July-August (Folder 17)
          - August (day unknown) (Folder 18)
          - August 10 (Folder 19)
          - September (day unknown) (Folder 20-21)
          - October 15 (Folder 22)
        - 1920
          - February 19 (Folder 23)
          - March 14 (Folder 24)
          - March 22 (Folder 25)
          - May 25 (Folder 26-27)
          - (ca.), July 12-13 (Folder 28)
          - (ca.), July 27-31 (Folder 29)
          - August (day unknown) (Folder 30)
          - (ca.), August 1-25 (Folder 31)
          - August 7 (Folder 32)
          - August 12 (Folder 33)
          - August 17 (Folder 34)
          - (ca.), August 17-18 (Folder 35)
        - 1921
          - February 6 (Folder 36)
          - February 12 (Folder 37)
          - March 3 (Folder 38)
          - March 25 (Folder 39)
          - April 9 (Folder 40-41)
          - May 30 (Folder 42)
          - (ca.), June-July (Folder 43)
        - Undated, 1922 (Folder 44)
      - Smilga, Ivan
        - 1919
          - August 13 (Folder 45)
          - October 4 (Folder 46)
          - October 5 (Folder 47)
        - 1920
          - February 17 (Folder 48)
          - February 28 (Folder 49)
          - March 3 (Folder 50)
          - March 11 (Folder 51)
          - March 17 (Folder 52)
          - May 12 (Folder 53)
          - July 20 (Folder 54)
          - August 3 (Folder 55)
          - August 18 (Folder 56)
          - August 20 (Folder 57-58)
          - August 24 (Folder 59)
      - Smirnov, Ivan, 1920
        - January 29 (Folder 60)
        - (ca.), February 7-29 (Folder 61)
        - March 10 (Folder 62)
        - April 20 (Folder 63)
        - August 2 (Folder 64)
      - Sokol'nikov, Grigorii, 1919
        - April 20 (Folder 65)
        - April 24 (Folder 66)
        - May 6 (Folder 67)
        - May 14 (Folder 68)
        - May 19 (Folder 69)
        - May 20 (Folder 70-71)
        - June 5 (Folder 72)
      - Somov, O., 1919 June 14 (Folder 73)
      - Stalin, Joseph, 1922 April 15 (Folder 74)
      - TSK RKP(b), 1921 January 20 (Folder 75)
      - TSK RKP(b) Politbiuro
        - 1921 December 19 (Folder 76)
        - 1922
          - March 23 (Folder 77)
          - April 11 (Folder 78)
      - Unshlikht, Iosif, 1920 March 11 (Folder 79)
      - Ural'skii Voenno-Revoliutsionnyi Komitet, 1920 August 2 (Folder 80)
      - Vatsetis, Ioakim, 1919 April 22 (Folder 81)
      - Vladimirov, Miron, 1921 July 28 (Folder 82)
      - Voroshilov, Kliment, 1921 May 5 (Folder 83)
      - Zatonskii, Vladimir, 1920 August 19 (Folder 84)
      - Zinov'ev, Grigorii, 1920 February 17 (Folder 85)
    - Others to V. I. Lenin
      - Bonch-Bruevich, Mikhail, 1919 June 10 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Chekasskii, 1921 March 18 (Folder 2)
      - Chicherin, Georgii
        - 1919 October 22 (Folder 3)
        - 1920 April 2 (Folder 4)
        - 1921 December 20 (Folder 5)
      - Egorov, Aleksandr, 1918 August 20 (Folder 6)
      - Frumkin, Moisei, 1922 December 15 (Folder 7)
      - Frunze, Mikhail, 1920
        - October 3 (Folder 8)
        - October 18 (Folder 9)
      - Ganetskii, Iakov, 1920
        - May 28 (Folder 10)
        - May 29 (Folder 11)
      - Kamenev, Sergei, 1919 October 22 (Folder 12)
      - Karakhan, Lev, 1918 February 2 (Folder 13)
      - Martynov, Ivan, 1921 March 19 (Folder 14)
      - Ordzhonikidze, Grigorii, 1920 September 24 (Folder 15-16)
      - Podvoiskii, Nikolai, 1917 December 13 (Folder 17)
      - Potiaev, Andrei, 1919 December 18 (Folder 18)
      - Protasov, Aleksandr, 1921 March 25 (Folder 19)
      - Rakovskii, Khristian, 1919 June 11 (Folder 20)
      - Raskol'nikov, F., 1919 September 6 (Folder 21)
      - Sadoul, Jacques, 1920 September 19 (Folder 22)
      - Shaposhnikov, Boris, 1919 December 15 (Folder 23)
      - Shatunovskii, Ia. M., 1922 October 5 (Folder 24)
      - Shliapnikov, Aleksandr, 1919 November 19 (Folder 25)
      - Sklianskii, Efraim, 1921
        - May (day unknown) (Folder 26)
        - (ca.), June 14-15 (Folder 27)
        - September (day unknown) (Folder 28)
        - November (day unknown) (Folder 29)
      - Smirnov, Ivan
        - 1920
          - March 9 (Folder 30)
          - September 22 (Folder 31)
          - September 23 (Folder 32)
        - 1921
          - March 18 (Folder 33)
          - March 25 (Folder 34)
      - Stalin, Joseph
        - (ca.), 1919 July 20-21 (Folder 35)
        - 1920
          - June 2 (Folder 36)
          - June 3 (Folder 37)
      - Sverdlov, Veniamin, 1919 December 23 (Folder 38)
      - Tukhachevskii, Mikhail, 1921 July 16 (Folder 39)
      - Vatsetis, Ioakim
        - 1918
          - August 24 (Folder 40)
          - December 14 (Folder 41)
          - December 28 (Folder 42)
        - 1919 April 21 (Folder 43)
      - Viktorov, B. K., 1919 December 15 (Folder 44)
    - Miscellaneous. Arranged alphabetically by writer and thereunder by addressee
      - Butov, Georgii, to Chicherin, Georgii, 1921 December 1 (Folder 45)
      - Chicherin, Georgii, to TSK RKP(b) Politbiuro, 1921 December 2 (Folder 46)
      - Fotieva, Lidiia, to Kamenev, Lev, 1923 April 16 (Folder 47)
      - Frumkin, Moisei, to Krestinskii, Nikolai, 1920 September 29 (Folder 48)
      - Iakovlev, Nikolai, to Karakhan, Lev, 1918 April 5 (Folder 49)
      - Kamenev, Sergei, to Sklianskii, Efraim, 1921
        - February 17 (Folder 50)
        - March 23 (Folder 51)
      - Kraevskii to Shaposhnikov, Boris, 1921 March 23 (Folder 52)
      - Kuz'min, N. N.
        - Chicherin, Georgii, 1920 February 29 (Folder 53)
        - Russian S.F.S.R. Revoliutsionnyi Voennyi Sovet Respubliki, 1920 March 3 (Folder 54)
      - Lashevich, Mikhail
        - Smilga, Ivan, 1919 June 19 (Folder 55)
        - TSK RKP(b), 1919 July 3 (Folder 56)
      - Obolenskii, Valerian, to TSK RKP(b), 1921 May 11 (Folder 57)
      - Pugachev, Semen, to Russian S.F.S.R. Revoliutsionnyi Voennyi Sovet Respubliki, 1921 February 17 (Folder 58)
      - Russian S.F.S.R. Revoliutsionnyi Voennyi Sovet Respubliki to Krupskii, Mikhail, 1920 February 17 (Folder 59)
      - Sergeev, I., to TSK RKP(b) Politbiuro, 1920 September 24 (Folder 60)
      - Sklianskii, Efraim
        - Danishevskii, Karl, 1920
          - August 25 (Folder 61)
          - August 26 (Folder 62)
        - Russian S.F.S.R. Revoliutsionnyi Voennyi Sovet Respubliki (Zapfront), 1920 August 23 (Folder 63)
        - Smirnov, Ivan, 1921 February 21 (Folder 64)
      - Sokol'nikov, Grigorii, to TSK RKP(b) Politbiuro, 1922 January 31 (Folder 65)
      - Stalin, Joseph, to Molotov, Viacheslav, 1922 March 10 (Folder 66)
      - Thalheimer, August, to TSK RKP(b), 1921 June 16 (Folder 67)
      - Tsiurupa, Aleksandr, to Murav'ev, 1920 February 21 (Folder 68)
      - Unshlikht, Iosif, to Russian S.F.S.R. Sovet Truda i Oborony, 1920 June 20 (Folder 69)
      - Vatsetis, Ioakim, to Volkov, Sergei, 1918 December 25 (Folder 70)
      - Vladimirov, Miron, to Tsiurupa, Aleksandr, 1921 March 2 (Folder 71-72)
      - Volin, Boris, to Sverdlov, Iakov, 1918 December 21 (Folder 73)
  - Miscellany. Arranged by writer
    - Bonch-Bruevich, Mikhail. Memorandum, 1919 June 1 (Folder 74)
    - Chicherin, Georgii. Memorandum, 1921 December 2 (Folder 75)
    - Kamenev, Sergei. Memoranda
      - (ca.), 1920 September 23-24 (Folder 76)
      - 1921 March 23 (Folder 77)
    - Lapinskii, Stanislav. Memorandum, (ca.), 1920 July 12-24 (Folder 78)
    - Lenin, V. I.
      - Endorsement for Trotsky, (day unknown), 1919 July (Folder 79)
      - Memorandum, (ca.), 1919 December 11-17 (Folder 80)
      - Order, 1920 January 21 (Folder 81)
      - Memorandum, (ca.), 1920 October 1-3 (Folder 82)
      - Memorandum, (day unknown), 1920 November (Folder 83)
      - Memorandum, 1922 March 9 (Folder 84)
      - Memoranda, 1922 December 27-29 (Folder 85)
    - Rossiiskaia Kommunisticheskaia Partiia (bol'shevikov). Draft program, 1919 March (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Russian S.F.S.R. Tsentral'nyi Ispolnitel'nyi Komitet, and Moskovskii Sovet. Joint resolution, 1918 June 17 (Folder 2)
    - TSK RKP(b). Excerpts from minutes of meetings
      - 1919
        - March 16 (Folder 3)
        - March 25 (Folder 4)
        - April 13 (Folder 5)
        - July 3 (Folder 6)
      - 1923
        - February 21 (Folder 7)
        - February 22 (Folder 8)
        - February 24 (Folder 9)
    - TSK RKP(b) Orgbiuro. Excerpts from minutes of meetings, 1919
      - April 20 (Folder 10)
      - May 7 (Folder 11)
    - TSK RKP(b) Politbiuro. Excerpts from minutes of meetings unless otherwise noted
      - 1919
        - April 18 (Folder 12)
        - May 26 (Folder 13)
        - August 6 (Folder 14)
        - October 15 (Folder 15)
        - October 23 (Folder 16)
        - October 26 (Folder 17)
        - November 14 (Folder 18)
        - December 31 (Folder 19)
      - 1920 August 19 (Folder 20)
      - Opinions of individual members 1923, 1922 April 18-19. (Folder 21)
        - February 8 (Folder 22)
        - February 20 (Folder 23)
        - March 1 (Folder 24)
        - March 8 (Folder 25)
        - March 22 (Folder 26)
    - TSK RKP(b) Politbiuro, and TSK RKP(b) Orgbiuro, 1919
      - Excerpts from minutes of joint meeting, May 22 (Folder 27)
      - Excerpts from minutes of joint meeting, June 2 (Folder 28)
      - Joint resolution, July 5 (Folder 29)
      - Excerpts from minutes of enlarged meeting, August 6 (Folder 30)
    - TSK RKP(b) Sekretariat. Proposals, 1923 January 29 (Folder 31)
    - Trotsky, Leon
      - Order, 1918 August 9 (Folder 32)
      - Message to troops, 1918 August 27 (Folder 33)
      - Excerpt from speech, 1918 September 12 (Folder 34)
      - "Nashe otnoshenie k borot'bistam," (ca.), 1919 December 11-17 (Folder 35)
      - Memorandum, 1921 November 16 (Folder 36)
      - "K voprosu o kreditivaniiu pod osnovnoi kapital,", 1923 February 12 (Folder 37)
      - Memorandum, 1923 February 15 (Folder 38)
      - "Tezisy o promyshlennosti,", 1923 March 6 (Folder 39)
      - Memorandum, 1923 November 15 (Folder 40)
      - Memoranda, 1924 July (Folder 41)
- LEON TROTSKY CORRESPONDENCE, 1926-1940. (Box 9-13)
  Correspondence of Leon Trotsky, divided into outgoing and incoming correspondence, and arranged within each division alphabetically by name of correspondent. See also V. I. LENIN FILE/Correspondence
  - Outgoing
    - American Committee for the Defense of Leon Trotsky, 1937
      - January 11 (Box 9, Folder 42)
      - March 17 (Folder 43)
      - March 28 (Folder 44)
    - Bardin, Alexis, 1938 June 9 (Folder 45)
    - British and International Press Ltd., 1937 July 4 (Folder 46)
    - Bukharin, Nikolai, 1926
      - January 8 (Folder 47)
      - March 4 (Folder 48)
    - Burnham, James, 1937
      - June 25 (Folder 49)
      - December 6 (Folder 50-51)
      - December 15 (Folder 52)
    - Cannon, James P.
      - 1937 December 24 (Folder 53)
      - 1938
        - February 15 (Folder 54)
        - April 5 (Folder 55)
      - 1939
        - March 27 (Folder 56)
        - April 8 (Folder 57)
    - Carolina Political Union, 1937 July 28 (Folder 58)
    - Chautemps, Camille, 1937 November 12 (Folder 59)
    - Ciliga, Ante, 1936 January 2 (Folder 60)
    - Communist League of America
      - 1930
        - January 6 (Folder 61)
        - March 26 (Folder 62)
      - 1931 December 25 (Folder 63)
      - 1932
        - January 5 (Folder 64)
        - May 19 (Folder 65)
        - May 27 (Folder 66)
        - October 20 (Folder 67)
      - 1934 March 29 (Folder 68)
    - Curtiss, Charles, 1939
      - January 18 (Folder 69)
      - February 15 (Folder 70)
    - Dewar, Hugo, 1936
      - March 7 (Folder 71)
      - April 9 (Folder 72)
    - Dobbs, Farrell, 1940
      - January 10 (Folder 73)
      - March 4 (Folder 74)
      - March 20 (Folder 75)
      - April 4 (Folder 76)
      - April 16 (Folder 77)
    - Dunayevskaya, Raya
      - 1937 June 12 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - 1938
        - June 20 (Folder 2)
        - June 29 (Folder 3)
        - August 27 (Folder 4)
        - November 3 (Folder 5)
      - 1939
        - March 29 (Folder 6)
        - April 20 (Folder 7)
        - November 14 (Folder 8)
    - Eastman, Max, 1931 January 2 (Folder 9)
    - Farrar and Rinehart (Publishers), 1937 March 15 (Folder 10)
    - Farrell, James T., 1937 November 8 (Folder 11)
    - Fourth International, 1940
      - February 1 (Folder 12)
      - February 20 (Folder 13)
    - Fourth International. Pan American Commission, 1939 March 22 (Folder 14)
    - Frank, Pierre, 1940 July 1 (Folder 15)
    - Frankel, Jan
      - Inscriptions, 1931-1936. (Folder 16)
      - 1933
        - January 15 (Folder 17)
        - February 22 (Folder 18)
        - March 8 (Folder 19)
        - April 3 (Folder 20-21)
        - April 12 (Folder 22)
        - April 14 (Folder 23)
        - April 18 (Folder 24)
        - April 21 (Folder 25)
        - April 27 (Folder 26)
        - April 29 (Folder 27)
        - May 8 (Folder 28)
        - May 11 (Folder 29)
        - May 21 (Folder 30)
        - May 26 (Folder 31)
        - (ca.), June-July (Folder 32)
        - July 5 (Folder 33)
        - November 26 (Folder 34)
      - 1935
        - November 25 (Folder 35)
        - December 11 (Folder 36)
        - December 15 (Folder 37)
        - December 24 (Folder 38)
        - December 30 (Folder 39)
        - December 31 (Folder 40)
      - 1936
        - January 24 (Folder 41)
        - April 28 (Folder 42)
        - October 2 (Folder 43)
      - 1937
        - November 3 (Folder 44)
        - December 21 (Folder 45)
      - 1938
        - January 26 (Folder 46)
        - January 30 (Folder 47)
        - February 3 (Folder 48)
        - February 7 (Folder 49)
        - March 16 (Folder 50)
        - March 30 (Folder 51)
        - April 29 (Folder 52)
        - May 14 (Folder 53)
        - June 5 (Folder 54)
        - June 13 (Folder 55)
      - 1939
        - April 12 (Folder 56)
        - May 10 (Folder 57)
    - Glotzer, Albert
      - 1937 September 18 (Folder 58)
      - 1939 February 14 (Folder 59)
    - Goldman, Albert
      - 1937
        - April 28 (Folder 60)
        - September 5 (Folder 61)
        - December 21 (Folder 62)
      - 1939 March 24 (Folder 63)
      - 1940
        - January 11 (Folder 64)
        - February 10 (Folder 65)
        - February 19 (Folder 66)
        - April 2 (Folder 67)
        - May 3 (Folder 68)
        - May 14 (Folder 69)
        - July 3 (Folder 70)
        - July 9 (Folder 71)
        - July 17 (Folder 72)
        - July 18 (Folder 73)
        - July 23 (Folder 74)
        - July 27 (Folder 75-76)
        - August 1 (Folder 77)
        - August 9 (Folder 78-79)
        - August 12 (Folder 80)
        - August 17 (Folder 81)
    - Groupe Bolchevique-Leniniste (France)
      - 1935 September 7 (Folder 82)
      - 1936 January 4 (Folder 83)
    - Hansen, Joseph
      - 1939
        - February 14 (Folder 84)
        - April 24 (Folder 85)
        - May 10 (Folder 86)
      - (ca.) Inscription, 1939-1940 (Folder 87)
      - 1940
        - January 5 (Folder 88)
        - January 18 (Folder 89)
        - February 29 (Folder 90)
    - Harper and Brothers (Publishers), 1937 February 20 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Harvard University, 1940 February 14 (Folder 2)
    - Heisler, Francis
      - 1937
        - March 13 (Folder 3)
        - September 28 (Folder 4)
      - 1938 June 4 (Folder 5)
    - Held, Walter
      - 1933
        - May 4 (Folder 6)
        - June 13 (Folder 7)
        - June 24 (Folder 8)
        - November 2 (Folder 9)
        - November 7 (Folder 10)
        - November 20 (Folder 11)
        - November 30 (Folder 12)
        - December 18 (Folder 13)
      - 1934 January 29 (Folder 14)
    - Holm og Rode (Law firm), 1938 February 7 (Folder 15)
    - International Communist League
      - 1935
        - January 31 (Folder 16)
        - June 10-13 (Folder 17)
        - October 3 (Folder 18)
        - October 21 (Folder 19)
        - December 15 (Folder 20)
      - 1938 January 21 (Folder 21)
    - International Communist League. Australian Section, 1937 December 23 (Folder 22)
    - International Communist League. Belgian Section, (day unknown), 1934 August (Folder 23)
    - International Left Opposition
      - 1931
        - January 31 (Folder 24)
        - March 7 (Folder 25)
      - 1932 June 9 (Folder 26)
      - 1933 April 17 (Folder 27)
    - International Left Opposition. Belgian Section, 1930 October 12 (Folder 28)
    - International Left Opposition. Bulgarian Section
      - 1930 October 4 (Folder 29)
      - 1932 March 29 (Folder 30)
    - International Left Opposition. Chinese Section, 1931 January 8 (Folder 31)
    - International Left Opposition. Spanish Section, 1932 March 7 (Folder 32)
    - Isaacs, Harold R., 1937
      - February 25 (Folder 33)
      - June 12 (Folder 34)
    - James, C. L. R., 1939 March 29 (Folder 35)
    - Juin 36, 1939 July 25 (Folder 36)
    - Kahlo, Frida, 1939 January 12 (Folder 37)
    - Karsner, Rose
      - 1939
        - January 9 (Folder 38)
        - February 20 (Folder 39)
        - June 5 (Folder 40)
        - September 1 (Folder 41)
        - September 28 (Folder 42)
      - 1940 July 27 (Folder 43)
    - Kay, Mr., 1940 August 3 (Folder 44)
    - Kitain, Hyman, 1937 April 28 (Folder 45)
    - Kluger, Pearl, 1937 October 6 (Folder 46)
    - Kopp, George, 1938 May 31 (Folder 47)
    - LaFollette, Suzanne
      - 1937
        - March 15 (Folder 48)
        - July 4 (Folder 49)
        - September 29 (Folder 50)
      - 1938 January 30 (Folder 51)
    - Langer, William L., 1939 November 6 (Folder 52)
    - League of Nations, 1938 March 31 (Folder 53)
    - Lesoil, Leon, 1935 March 24 (Folder 54)
    - Ligue Communiste (France), 1930 December 22 (Folder 55)
    - Lunacharskii, Anatolii, 1926 April 14 (Folder 56)
    - La Lutte Ouvriere, 1937 March 23 (Folder 57)
    - Macdonald, Dwight, 1938 January 20 (Folder 58)